<xml>
<!-- add new wavlengths below (Visible needs to be at the top) -->
<config>
	<start><![CDATA[<b>About this activity</b>
The aim of this activity is to match images of an astronomical object, observed in different wavelengths, with the object's visible image (a composite image made up of a red, green and blue images).
		
<b>Where to start...</b>

1. Select an image set from the Object list and click <b>[Load New Object]</b>. This object's visible image will then be displayed.

2. Select a wavelength from the options above to see a random grid of images of objects in that wavelength. Click on an image in the grid to compare your selection with the visible image. If you think it is a match click <b>[Select Image]</b>. You can change your selection by going through the same process. Think about the object such as its shape and size in the new different wavelengths. What could that visible object, now in a different wavelength, reveal?

3. Once you have selected an image from each of the available wavelengths click <b>[Check Answers]</b> to see if your selections are correct. More Information about the object, such as its history and what the different wavelengths images reveal about the object, will then become available.
	]]></start>
    <wavelengths>
        <wl>
            <title>Visible</title>
            <dir>visible</dir>
        </wl>
        <wl>
            <title>Radio</title>
            <dir>radio</dir>
        </wl>
        <wl>
            <title>Far Infra-red</title>
            <dir>fir</dir>
        </wl>
        <wl>
            <title>Mid Infra-red</title>
            <dir>mir</dir>
        </wl>
        <wl>
            <title>Near Infra-red</title>
            <dir>nir</dir>
        </wl>
        <wl>
            <title>Ultraviolet</title>
            <dir>uv</dir>
        </wl>
        <wl>
            <title>X-ray</title>
            <dir>xray</dir>
        </wl>
    </wavelengths>
</config> 

<objects>
    
    <object>	
        <name>Centaurus A</name>
	<images>
	  <ID>0</ID>
	  <visible>cena_vis_square.png</visible>
	  <radio>cenA_radio_vla.gif</radio>
	  <fir>cenA_fir_herschel.jpg</fir>
	  <mir>cena_mir-square_spitzer.jpg</mir>
	  <uv>cena_uv_galex.jpg</uv>
	  <xray>cena_xray_chandra.jpg</xray>
        </images>
	<credits>
	  <visible><![CDATA[NOAO]]></visible>
	  <fir><![CDATA[Herschel]]></fir>
	  <radio><![CDATA[VLA]]></radio>
	  <mir><![CDATA[Spitzer]]></mir>
	  <uv><![CDATA[GALEX]]></uv>
	  <xray><![CDATA[Chandra]]></xray>
	</credits>
	<coord>
	  <ra>201.375</ra>
	  <dec>-43.017</dec>
	</coord>
        <info><![CDATA[This object is Centaurus A, a large elliptical galaxy 11 million light years from Earth.  Lying in the constellation of Centaurus the Centaur, the galaxy is particularly notable because of the dark lanes of dust stretching across the enormous ball of stars.  When viewed in mid-infrared light, this dust is seen to be glowing, while the stars become invisible.  At longer far-infrared wavelengths, the dust is still seen, but there are two perculiar jets eminating from the centre of the galaxy.  These are the same jets as seen in the radio and x-ray images, and are composed of very energetic particles which have been ejected from the galaxy by the massive black hole in its centre.  They stretch for 13,000 light years into intergalactic space, and will have a strong impact on the behaviour of the galaxy, such as the rate at which it is forming stars.  Similar jets are seen in many other galaxies, and imply that the black hole is actively accreting material from its immediate surroundings. Centaurus A is the closest example of an "active galaxy".]]></info>
    </object>
    
    <object>
        <name>The Crab Nebula</name>
        <images>
	  <ID>1</ID>
	  <visible>crab_vis_vlt.jpg</visible>
	  <radio>crab_radio_NRAO.gif</radio>
	  <fir>crab_fir_Herschel-PACS.jpg</fir>
	  <mir>crab_mir_spitzer.jpg</mir>
	  <uv>crab_uv_UIT.jpg</uv>
	  <xray>crab_xray-square_chandra.jpg</xray>
        </images>
	<credits>
	  <visible><![CDATA[VLT]]></visible>
	  <fir><![CDATA[Herschel-PACS]]></fir>
	  <radio><![CDATA[NRAO]]></radio>
	  <mir><![CDATA[Spitzer]]></mir>
	  <uv><![CDATA[UIT]]></uv>
	  <xray><![CDATA[Chandra]]></xray>
	</credits>
	<coord>
	  <ra>83.625</ra>
	  <dec>22.017</dec>
	</coord>
        <info><![CDATA[This is the Crab Nebula, so called because the Earl of Rosse thought it looked like a crab.  We now know that it is a "supernova remnant", which is all that remains of a massive star which exploded.  In the case of the Crab Nebula, we know that the star exploded in 1054 AD, and was observed by Chinese and Arabic astronomers.  Such a violent explosion, would have briefly changed the face of the constellation of Taurus, but at a distance of around 6,500 light years would have had no effect on the Earth itself.  The material which made up the star was thrown out into the surrounding space, and the visible light image shows the resulting cloud of gas, laced through with small amounts of dust.  The gas is glowing at visible, ultraviolet, far-infrared and radio wavelengths.  The x-ray image shows a swirling disc of material, at the centre of which lies the only solid remains of the star.  This very dense "neutron star" is around the same mass as the Sun, but is only around 20km across.  It spins on its axis 30 times a second, and as it does so it sends beams of radio waves and x-rays out of its poles.  Thes beams happen to pass over the Earth once every revolution, much like a lighthouse beam, causing what astronomers call a "pulsar".<br><br>The Crab Nebula is just visible in binoculars from a dark site, and a small telescope will bring out its diffuse nature, though larger telescopes and long exposure photographs are neaded to produce the vivid colours seen here.]]></info>
    </object>
    
    <object>	
        <name>Antennae</name>
	<images>
	  <ID>2</ID>
	  <visible>antennae_vis_hst.jpg</visible>
	  <fir>antennae_fir_Herschel-PACS_small.jpg</fir>
	  <radio>antennae_radio_vla.jpg</radio>
	  <mir>antennae_mir_spitzer.jpg</mir>
	  <xray>antennae_xray_chandra.jpg</xray>
        </images>
	<credits>
	  <visible><![CDATA[Hubble]]></visible>
	  <fir><![CDATA[Herschel-PACS]]></fir>
	  <radio><![CDATA[VLA]]></radio>
	  <mir><![CDATA[Spitzer]]></mir>
	  <xray><![CDATA[Chandra]]></xray>
	</credits>
	<coord>
	  <ra>180.47</ra>
	  <dec>-18.169</dec>
	</coord>
        <info><![CDATA[This bizarre looking galaxy is actually two galaxies, which individually go by the catalogue names of NGC 4038 and NGC 4039.  The galaxies are in the process of merging, and the two bright central bulges can be seen in the upper right and lower left of the visible light image.  The two galaxies have been severely disrupted by each other, and their gravitational pull has stripped stars out to form huge "tidal tails" of stars and dust.  These are more apparent in wider views, and are what lead to them being called the "antennae".  Discovered by William Herschel in 1785, they lie around 50 million lightyears away in the constellation of Corvus the Crow.  The collision of massive clouds of gas and dust has lead to a bout of star formation, which causes the gas and dust to be warmed and therefore glow at mid-infrared, far-infrared and radio wavelengths. The x-ray image shows very energetic material, with the bright spots being particular types binary star systems.  When one star in a binary system has died and become either a white dwarf, a neutron star, or even a black hole, it can pull material off its companion star.  This heats the material to immense temperatures and causes it to emit x-rays, forming what are called "x-ray binary stars".<br><br>A small telescope will show the antennae galaxies, and a long-exposure photograph through a medium-sized telescope should show their distinctive shape.]]></info>
    </object>
    
    <object>	
      <name>Cassiopeia A</name>
      <images>
	<ID>3</ID>
	<visible>casa_vis_hst.jpg</visible>
	<fir>casA_fir_Herschel-PACS.jpg</fir>
	<radio>casA_radio_NRAO.gif</radio>
	<mir>casA_mir_spitzer.jpg</mir>
	<xray>casa_xray_chandra.jpg</xray>
      </images>
	<credits>
	  <visible><![CDATA[Hubble]]></visible>
	  <fir><![CDATA[Herschel-PACS]]></fir>
	  <radio><![CDATA[VLA]]></radio>
	  <mir><![CDATA[Spitzer]]></mir>
	  <xray><![CDATA[Chandra]]></xray>
	</credits>
	<coord>
	  <ra>350.858</ra>
	  <dec>0.98</dec>
	</coord>
      <info><![CDATA[Cassiopeia A is the remnant of a supernova explosion that occured over 300 years ago in our Galaxy, at a distance of about 11,000 light years from Earth. Its name is comes from the constellation in which it is seen; Cassiopeia, a Queen in Greek mythology. Cassiopeia A is one of the brightest radio sources in the sky over 1 Ghz but at visible wavelengths is is quite faint. X-ray imaging shows an expanding shell of hot gas produced by the explosion. This gaseous shell is about 10 light years in diameter, and has a temperature of about 50 million degrees Moreover, due to the supernova explosion, Cassiopeia A is expanding at a rate betweeen 4,000-6,000 kilometers per second. Before the supernova explosion Cassiopeia A was an original star like our Sun with a mass of approximately 15 to 20 solar masses.]]></info>
    </object>
    
    <object>	
      <name>Large Magellanic Cloud</name>
      <images>
	<ID>4</ID>
	<visible>lmc_vis_square.png</visible>
	<fir>lmc_fir_iras.jpg</fir>
	<radio>lmc_radio_rauib.gif</radio>
	<uv>lmc_uv_rocket.jpg</uv>
	<xray>lmc_xray_rosat.gif</xray>
      </images>
	<credits>
	  <visible><![CDATA[]]></visible>
	  <fir><![CDATA[IRAS]]></fir>
	  <radio><![CDATA[RAUIB]]></radio>
	  <uv><![CDATA[Rocket]]></uv>
	  <xray><![CDATA[ROSAT]]></xray>
	</credits>
	<coord>
	  <ra>79.75</ra>
	  <dec>-69</dec>
	</coord>
      <info><![CDATA[This object is the Large Magellanic Cloud(LMC).The object was named after a Portuguese navigator called Ferdinand Magellan who first sailed around the world. It is a small galaxy that is about 200,000 light years from earth and orbits the Milky Way. Traditionally classified as an irregular galaxy new evidence suggests that it is in fact a barred spiral galaxy. In 1987 an exploding star call Supernova 1987a was observed in the LMC which was the closest supernove observed since 1604. The LMC is also a region of active star formation scattered with glowing nebula including the Tarantula Nebula the brightest stellar nursery in our cosmic neighbourhood. A very interesting fact is that the LMC is gravitationally attached to the Milky way galaxy. This is because the Milky way is much bigger when compared to the LMC.  ]]></info>
    </object>

    <object>	
      <name>Andromeda</name>
      <images>
	<ID>5</ID>
	<visible>m31_vis_gendler_rot.jpg</visible>
	<fir>m31_fir_herschel.jpg</fir>
	<radio>m31_radio_effelsberg.jpg</radio>
	<uv>m31_uv_galex.jpg</uv>
	<mir>m31_mir_spitzer_rot.jpg</mir>
	<xray>m31_xray_xmm.jpg</xray>
      </images>
	<credits>
	  <visible><![CDATA[Rob Gendler]]></visible>
	  <fir><![CDATA[Herschel]]></fir>
	  <radio><![CDATA[Effelsberg]]></radio>
	  <uv><![CDATA[GALEX]]></uv>
	  <mir><![CDATA[Spitzer]]></mir>
	  <xray><![CDATA[XMM-Newton]]></xray>
	</credits>
	<coord>
	  <ra>10.657</ra>
	  <dec>41.267</dec>
	</coord>
      <info><![CDATA[This object is the Andromeda Galaxy a spiral galaxy which is the closet large galaxy to the Milky Way at 2.5 million light years away. Also known as Messier 31 (M31), it is moving towards the Milky Way at around 120 kilometers per hour and the two galaxies are expected to collide in around 4.5 billion years.This is because the mysterious matter, called 'Dark matter', between them attracts them to one another.  It gets its name from the region of the sky in which it appears; the constellation of Andromeda. Whilst is the largest galaxy in the local group, it may not be the most massive as recent findings suggest the Milk Way contains more dark matter making it the  most massive in the local group. It contains around a trillion stars; more than double the number found in the Milky Way. Andromeda can be seen from the naked eye on a clear night sky. ]]></info>
    </object>

    <object>	
      <name>Triangulum</name>
      <images>
	<ID>6</ID>
	<visible>m33_vis_gendler.jpg</visible>
	<radio>m33_radio_nrao.jpg</radio>
	<mir>m33_mir_spitzer.jpg</mir>
	<uv>m33_uv_UIT.jpg</uv>
	<xray>m33_xray_rosat.jpg</xray>
      </images>
	<credits>
	  <visible><![CDATA[Rob Gendler]]></visible>
	  <radio><![CDATA[NRAO]]></radio>
	  <mir><![CDATA[Spitzer]]></mir>
	  <uv><![CDATA[UIT]]></uv>
	  <xray><![CDATA[ROSAT]]></xray>
	</credits>
	<coord>
	  <ra>23.475</ra>
	  <dec>30.65</dec>
	</coord>
      <info><![CDATA[This object is the Triangulum Galaxy also known as M33 and is approximately 3 million light-years from Earth. Triangulum was given the nickname the 'Pinwheel galaxy' because of its appearance and it is the most frequent viewed galaxy with the naked eye. It is a spiral galaxy located in the constellation of Triangulum and spans approximately 50,000 light-years. It is approaching the Milky Way galax at approximately 24 kilometers per hour. This galaxy contains around 40 billion stars and is the third largest galaxy in the Local Group containing many star-forming regions. The mass of the Triangulum Galaxy ia estimated to be between 10 and 40 billion solar masses. The nucleus of this galaxy is a star forming region, and it contains an ultraluminous X-ray source being the  most luminous source of X-rays in the Local Group. However, the nucleus does not appear to contain a supermassive black hole]]></info>
    </object>

    <object>	
      <name>Orion</name>
      <images>
	<ID>7</ID>
	<visible>m42_vis_hst.jpg</visible>
	<fir>m42_microwave_planck.jpg</fir>
	<nir>m42_nir_vista.jpg</nir>
	<mir>m42_mir_spitzer.jpg</mir>
	<xray>m42_xray_XMM.jpg</xray>
      </images>
	<credits>
	  <visible><![CDATA[Hubble]]></visible>
	  <fir><![CDATA[Planck]]></fir>
	  <nir><![CDATA[VISTA]]></nir>
	  <mir><![CDATA[Spitzer]]></mir>
	  <xray><![CDATA[XMM-Newton]]></xray>
	</credits>
	<coord>
	  <ra>83.85</ra>
	  <dec>-5.45</dec>
	</coord>
      <info><![CDATA[This object is the Orion Nebula also known as M42 and is around 1,344 light years from earth. It is a glowing emission nebula, one of the brightest visible to the naked eye, and has a greenish hue. Its position in the sky is just below Orions belt. It is a region of massive star formation with a mass of aproximately 2000 solar masses and is the nearest star formation to Earth making it well studied.  ]]></info>
    </object>

    <object>	
      <name>Messier 81</name>
      <images>
	<ID>8</ID>
	<visible>m81_vis_gendler.jpg</visible>
	<fir>m81_fir_herschel.png</fir>
	<radio>m81_radio_vla.jpg</radio>
	<uv>m81_uv_UIT.jpg</uv>
	<xray>m81_xray_chandra.jpg</xray>
      </images>
	<credits>
	  <visible><![CDATA[Rob Gendler]]></visible>
	  <fir><![CDATA[Herschel]]></fir>
	  <radio><![CDATA[VLA]]></radio>
	  <uv><![CDATA[UIT]]></uv>
	  <xray><![CDATA[Chandra]]></xray>
	</credits>
	<coord>
	  <ra>148.9</ra>
	  <dec>69.067</dec>
	</coord>
      <info><![CDATA[This object is the galaxy Messier 81. It is a spiral galaxy located in thr northern constellation of Ursa Major. It is located 12 million light years from earth making it one of the closest spiral galaxies to our Milky Wat and visible using a small telescope or binoculars. There is an unusually bright hot 'bulge' of stars at it centre which has basicall two possible explanations:- a) an encouner with a neighbouring galaxy cause interstellar gas to be comprssed due to gravity causing them to collapse and generate hot massive stars; b) the nucleus of M81 is a "mini-quasar" -- a disk of hot gas surrounding a supermassive black hole]]></info>
    </object>

    <object>	
      <name>Messier 82</name>
      <images>
	<ID>9</ID>
	<visible>M82_vis_gendler.jpg</visible>
	<fir>m82_fir_herschel.png</fir>
	<radio>M82_radio_vla-merlin.jpg</radio>
	<mir>m82_mir_spitzer_rot.jpg</mir>
	<uv>m82_uv_UIT.jpg</uv>
	<xray>m82_xray_chandra.jpg</xray>
      </images>
	<credits>
	  <visible><![CDATA[Rob Gendler]]></visible>
	  <fir><![CDATA[Herschel]]></fir>
	  <radio><![CDATA[VLA-MERLIN]]></radio>
	  <mir><![CDATA[Spitzer]]></mir>
	  <uv><![CDATA[UIT]]></uv>
	  <xray><![CDATA[Chandra]]></xray>
	</credits>
	<coord>
	  <ra>148.95</ra>
	  <dec>69.683</dec>
	</coord>
      <info><![CDATA[This object is the galaxy Messier 82. It is gravitationally bount to M81 and is therefore about the same distane away at 12 million light years. It is a relatively small galaxy having a mass of about one tenth of the Milky Way but is producing stars at a rate of about 10 time that of the Milky Way. It is known as a 'star burst' galaxy because of the high level of star formation and is therefore one of the brightest galaxies in the sky at infrared wavelengths. ]]></info>
    </object>

    <object>	
      <name>Messier 87</name>
      <images>
	<ID>10</ID>
	<visible>M87_vis_gendler.jpg</visible>
	<fir>m87_fir_herschel.png</fir>
	<radio>m87_radio_nrao.jpg</radio>
	<mir>m87_mir_iras.jpg</mir>
	<xray>m87_xray_chandra.jpg</xray>
      </images>
	<credits>
	  <visible><![CDATA[Rob Gendler]]></visible>
	  <fir><![CDATA[Herschel]]></fir>
	  <radio><![CDATA[NRAO]]></radio>
	  <mir><![CDATA[IRAS]]></mir>
	  <xray><![CDATA[Chandra]]></xray>
	</credits>
	<coord>
	  <ra>187.7</ra>
	  <dec>12.4</dec>
	</coord>
      <info><![CDATA[This object is the galaxy Messier 87 and is at the heart of a cluster of galaxies in the constellation of Virgo. Its distance from earth is 53.5 million light years and unlike the Milk Way, M87 is an elliptical galaxy. It contains little gas and dust and is composed mostly of cool stars that give it a yellowish colour. Because of the lack of star forming materals, star formation is relativel low. At the centre of the galaxy is a super massive black hole with emits high levels of x-rays in bursts every few millions of years. These outbursts cause shockwave in the gas and dust which prevent it cooling and forming new stars ]]></info>
    </object>

    <object>	
      <name>Messier 104</name>
      <images>
	<ID>11</ID>
	<visible>m104_vis_hst.png</visible>
	<nir>m104_nir_2mass.jpg</nir>
	<radio>m104_radio_vla_magfield.gif</radio>
	<mir>m104_mir_spitzer.jpg</mir>
	<xray>m104_xray_chandra.jpg</xray>
      </images>
	<credits>
	  <visible><![CDATA[Hubble]]></visible>
	  <nir><![CDATA[2MASS]]></nir>
	  <radio><![CDATA[VLA]]></radio>
	  <mir><![CDATA[Spitzer]]></mir>
	  <xray><![CDATA[Chandra]]></xray>
	</credits>
	<coord>
	  <ra>190</ra>
	  <dec>11.617</dec>
	</coord>
      <info><![CDATA[Messier 104, found in the Virgo constellation, is more commonly known as the Sombrero Galaxy, as the thick layer of dust makes it look like the mexican hat when seen in visible light. It is 50 million light years across and 20 million light years from Earth and is an unbarred spiral galaxy. Messier 104 is notable for having a very bright center with a well defined boarder and for having a dust lane. This is a galaxy that has never been explored and is unlikely to be due to its strong gravitational force. ]]></info>
    </object>
    
</objects>
</xml>
